Running `python manage.py dumpdata --natural --indent 2 --format=yaml core.question` attached to terminal... up, run.1
- fields:
    answer: "When they have the same length and same direction, even if the initial\
      \ andterminal points are not the same.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: Define when two vectors are equivalent.
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 1
- fields:
    answer: "<ul>\r\n<li> The midpoint is $\\frac{P+Q}{2} = (\\frac{9}{2}, -\\frac{1}{2},\
      \ -\\frac{1}{2}).$\r\n<li> The point $\\frac{3}{4}$ of the way from $P$ to $Q$\
      \ is $P + \\frac{3}{4}(Q - P) = \\frac{1}{4}P + \\frac{3}{4}Q = (\\frac{23}{4},\
      \ -\\frac{9}{4}, \\frac{1}{4}).$\r\n</ul>"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: X
    concepts: [3]
    index: 3.1.11
    points: 4
    question: "Let $P$ be the point $(2, 3, -2)$ and $Q$ be the point $(7, -4, 1)$.\r\
      \n<ul>\r\n<li> Find the midpoint of the line segment connecting $P$ and $Q$.\r\
      \n<li> Find the point on the line segment connecting $P$ and $Q$ that is $\\\
      frac{3}{4}$ of the way from $P$ to $Q$.\r\n</ul>"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 2
- fields:
    answer: "Suppose neither $a$ nor $b$ are 0. Then:\r\n\r\n$1 = 1/a 1/b ab = 1/a\
      \ 1/b 0 = 0$.\r\n\r\nThus we have a contradiction, and one of $a$ or $b$ is\
      \ zero."
    book: 3
    book_section: '1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: If $ab = 0$ and $a$ and $b$ are real numbers, what can you say?
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 3
- fields:
    answer: "A number is prime if $p > 1$ and its only positive divisors are $1$ and\
      \ $p$.\r\n"
    book: 3
    book_section: '1.2'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: Define a prime number $p \in \mathbb{N}$
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 4
- fields:
    answer: "$$3 \\times 14 = 42$$\r\n$$3 \\times 4 + 3 \\times 10 = 12 + 30 = 42$$\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '1.9'
    points: 2
    question: "Verify the distributive property\r\n\r\n$$3 \\times (4 + 10)$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 5
- fields:
    answer: "$$0$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '3.16'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify \r\n$$-3 \\cdot (-6 + 6)$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 6
- fields:
    answer: "$$4/15 + 7/48 = \\frac{4 \\times 16 + 7 \\times 5}{16 \\times 5 \\times\
      \ 3} = \\frac{48+35}{240} = \\frac{83}{240}$$\r\n$$1.41 + 0.564 + 0.0141 = 1.9881$$\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '4'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 4.12, 4.36
    points: 2
    question: "Simplify\r\n$$1/3 \\times 4/5 + 1/6 \\times 7/8$$\r\n$$1.41 \\times\
      \ 1.41$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 7
- fields:
    answer: "2, 3, 5, 7, 11, 13, 17, 19\r\n"
    book: 3
    book_section: '1.2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '1.2'
    points: 1
    question: List all prime numbers less than 20
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 8
- fields:
    answer: "If $a$ is divisible by $n$, then $a = kn$ and if $m$ is not then $m =\
      \ k'n + c$\r\nwhere $c \\ne 0$. Then note that $a + b = (k+k')n + c$, so $a+b$\
      \ is NOT\r\ndivisible by $n$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '1.37'
    points: 3
    question: "If you add one number divisible by $n$ and one number not divisible\
      \ by $n$,\r\nwill the result be divisible by $n? Explain."
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 9
- fields:
    answer: "When $a$ and $b$ have the same sign.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '3.39'
    points: 2
    question: "When does \r\n$$|a + b| = |a| + |b|?$$"
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 10
- fields:
    answer: "1) a + b = b + a\r\n2) (a + b) + c = a + (b + c)\r\n3) 0 + a = a\r\n\
      4) a + (-a) = 0\r\n5) a x b = b x a\r\n6) (a x b) x c = a x (b x c)\r\n7) a\
      \ x 1 = a\r\n8) a x (b + c) = a x b + a x c\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '1'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: '1'
    points: 4
    question: State the eight algebraic properties of the integers
    section: 41
  model: core.question
  pk: 11
- fields:
    answer: "Any correct transformation to two equal quantities results in two other\
      \ equal\r\nquantities."
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the golden rule\r\n"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 12
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = \\frac{d - b}{a - c}.$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '2.18'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve for $x$\r\n$$ax - b = cx + d.$$"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 13
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n$$ x + (x+1) + (x+2) = 75$$\r\n$$ 3x + 3 = 75$$\r\n$$ 3x = 72$$\r\
      \n$$  x = 24$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '2.29'
    points: 4
    question: "What three consecutive numbers add up to 75?\r\n"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 14
- fields:
    answer: "1. Reflexive: $a = a$.\r\n2. Symmetry: $a = b$ implies $b = a$.\r\n3.\
      \ Transitive: $a = b$ and $b = c$ implies $a = c$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "State the properties of equality.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 42
  model: core.question
  pk: 15
- fields:
    answer: "You can start with squares, cubes, etc. as very common operations (e.g.\
      \ area),\r\nand then notice that you can extend."
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the motivation behind exponent conventions.\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 16
- fields:
    answer: "Simplify:\r\n$$16a^3b^4c/(8a^3b^6c^2)$$"
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '5.21'
    points: 2
    question: "Simplify:\r\n$$16a^3b^4c/(8a^3b^6c^2)$$\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 17
- fields:
    answer: "$1.098 \\times 10^12$ cubic kilometers.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '5.33'
    points: 5
    question: "The volume of a sphere is given by the formula $(4/3\\pi r^3$,where\
      \ $\\pi$ is about 3.14 and $r$ is the radius of the sphere. The earth is approximately\
      \ a sphere with radius about $6400$ kilometers. What is the volume of the earth\
      \ (use scientific notation)?\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 18
- fields:
    answer: "$$x^a x^b = x^{a+b}$$\r\n$$(x^a)^b = x^{ab}$$\r\n$$\\frac{x^a}{x^b} =\
      \ x^{a-b}$$\r\n$$(xy)^a = x^ay^a$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '5'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 4
    question: "What are the Laws of Exponents?\r\n\r\n"
    section: 43
  model: core.question
  pk: 19
- fields:
    answer: "When examining the diagonal of a unit square\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give an example of how a square root arises in geometry.\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 20
- fields:
    answer: "$3/4$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '6.3'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify $\\sqrt{9/16}$.\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 21
- fields:
    answer: "$-3 - 2\\sqrt{2}$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '6.17'
    points: 1
    question: "Remove the radical from the denominator of $\\frac{1 + \\sqrt{2}}{1\
      \ - \\sqrt{2}}$.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 22
- fields:
    answer: "$\\frac{1}{4}$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '6'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '6.26'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify $\\sqrt[4]{1/256}$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 44
  model: core.question
  pk: 23
- fields:
    answer: "The goal is to simplify the complexity of the algebraic expression, by\
      \ either\r\nproducing fewer terms or perhaps fewer factors\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain the goal of the Algebraic Expression Rule\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 24
- fields:
    answer: "1. $(a + b)^2 = a^2 + 2ab + b^2$\r\n\r\n2. $(a - b)^2 = a^2 - 2ab + b^2$\r\
      \n\r\n3. $(a - b)(a + b) = a^2 - b^2$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "State 3 generic rules involving combining $(a+b)$ and $(a-b)$.\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 25
- fields:
    answer: "A collection of numbers and letters representing numbers that are connected\
      \ by arithmetic operation signs, such as $+$, $-$, $/$ or $\\cdot$.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an algebraic expression\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 26
- fields:
    answer: "The part of an algebraic expression that are separated by $\\pm$.\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a term\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 27
- fields:
    answer: "A 1-, 2-, or 3-term algebraic expression [resp.]\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define monomomial, binomial and trinomial algebraic expressions.\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 28
- fields:
    answer: "$$6x^2 + 2x + 12ax + 2a + 6a^2 - 4$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.23'
    points: 1
    question: "Multiply $[(2x + 1) + (2a + 1)][(3x - 1) + (3a - 1)]$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 29
- fields:
    answer: "$$1 + 3x + 3x^2 + x^3$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.25'
    points: 1
    question: "Multiply out $(1+x)^3$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 30
- fields:
    answer: "$$[x^2 - 6x + 9]/16 + [y^2 + 6y + 9]/9 = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.32'
    points: 3
    question: "Write the following algebraic expression in the form $Ax^2 + Bxy +\
      \ Cy^2 + Dx + Ey + F = 0$:\r\n$$(x - 3)^2/16 + (y + 3)^2/9 = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 31
- fields:
    answer: "$$= (155 - 154)(155 + 154) = 1 \\cdot 309 = 309$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '7.35'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate: 155^2 - 154^2 simply.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 32
- fields:
    answer: "Combine all of the like terms into one term.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Algebraic Expression Rule\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 33
- fields:
    answer: "$$a(b+c) = ab + bc$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Distributive property of algebraic expressions.\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 34
- fields:
    answer: "$$(a + b)(c + d) = ac + ad + bc + bd\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '7'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the FOIL method\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 45
  model: core.question
  pk: 35
- fields:
    answer: "Consider a table of values for common values: area versus side length,\
      \ fall\r\ntime versus drop height, etc. This will lead to the idea of a function\
      \ as a\r\nshortcut.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Give a motivation for the development of functions\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 36
- fields:
    answer: "A function $f$ is an assignment of a value $y$ to any quantity $x$. We\
      \ denote\r\nthis assignment as $y = f(x)$. The set of possible $x$ is called\
      \ the domain,\r\nand the set of possible $y$ is called the range.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Define a function, domain and range.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 37
- fields:
    answer: "$g$ is the inverse of $f$ if for all $x$, $f(g(x)) = x$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an inverse function\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 38
- fields:
    answer: "2, 1, $a^2 + 2a + 2$, $2xh + 2h + h^2$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '8'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 8.11, 13, 15, 17
    points: 4
    question: "Let $f(x) = x^2 + 2x + 2$. Evaluate: $f(0), $f(-1)$, $f(a)$, $f(x +\
      \ h) - f(x)$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 46
  model: core.question
  pk: 39
- fields:
    answer: "The first number is the distance east of the origin while the second\
      \ number is\r\nthe distance north."
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how a pair of numbers represents a point in a north-east plane.\r\
      \n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 40
- fields:
    answer: "A pair of numbers written $(x, y)$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an ordered pair\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 41
- fields:
    answer: "$$m = \\frac{ y_2 - y_1 }{ x_2 - x_1 }$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the slope of the line going between the points $(x_1, y_1)$\
      \ and $(x_2, y_2)$?\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 42
- fields:
    answer: "The y value of where the x-value is zero.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the y-intercept of a line\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 43
- fields:
    answer: "17.464\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '9.6'
    points: 1
    question: "What is the distance between $(16, 4)$ and $(0, -3)$?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 44
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 4
    question: "Draw the graph of $y = |x + 2| - 2$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 45
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 0, y = 10; x = 5, y = 0$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '9.16'
    points: 3
    question: "Find the coordinates of the points where the line $2x + y = 10$ cross\
      \ the $x$ and $y$ axes.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 46
- fields:
    answer: "$$(y - 1030)/(x - 1025) = 100; y = 100x - 101470$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '9.24'
    points: 5
    question: "Find the equation of a line with slope $100$ and passes through the\
      \ point $(1025, 1030)$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 47
- fields:
    answer: "$$d = \\sqrt{x^2 + y^2}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the distance from the origin of a point $(x, y)$?\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 48
- fields:
    answer: "$$d = \\sqrt{ (x_2 - x_1)^2 + (y_2 - y_1)^2 }$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the distance between two points $(x_1, y_1)$ and $(x_2, y_2)$.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 49
- fields:
    answer: "$$y = mx + b$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '9'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "If $m$ is the slope of a line and $b$ is the $y$-intercept, what is\
      \ the\r\nequation of the line?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 47
  model: core.question
  pk: 50
- fields:
    answer: "When two graphs (of $f$ and $g$) intersect, then $f(x) = g(x)$ thus it's\
      \ a\r\nsolution to two simultaneous equations."
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain what the intersection of two graphs represents?\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 51
- fields:
    answer: "Solve one equation for x, substitute this into the second, solve for\
      \ y, and\r\nthen back-solve for x."
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain how to solve a system of two linear equations\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 52
- fields:
    answer: "They are the same line.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "If two simultaneous linear equations have no solution what does this\
      \ say about the lines?\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 53
- fields:
    answer: "Two equations:\r\n$$y = f(x)$$\r\n$$y = g(x)$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a system of two simultaneous equations.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 54
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 4, y = 18$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 10.1 and 10.3
    points: 3
    question: "Solve the following systems of equations for x and y:\r\n\r\n$$y =\
      \ 10 + 2x$$\r\n$$y = 4.5x$$\r\n\r\n$$y = 10 + 2x$$\r\n$$y = 2x$$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 55
- fields:
    answer: "12 cows and 21 chickens\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '10'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '10.29'
    points: 4
    question: "Farmer Floran has a total 33 cows and chickens. Altogether the\r\n\
      animals have 90 feet. How many cows and how many chickens are there?\r\n\r\n"
    section: 48
  model: core.question
  pk: 56
- fields:
    answer: "If we can write $ax^2 + bx +c = d(x - e)(x - f) = 0$ then if $d \\ne\
      \ 0$, since\r\ntwo non-zero numbers cannot multiply to be zero (See\r\nAlgebra/000/Number_Properties)\
      \ one of $x - e = 0$ or $x - f = 0$, or\r\nequivalently, $ x = e $ or $x = f$."
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain how to solve a quadratic equation via factoring.\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 57
- fields:
    answer: "If the coefficients of the equation are all rational, then no.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Can a quadratic equation have one rational solution and one irrational?\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 58
- fields:
    answer: "If $b^2 - 4ac$ is a square.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give a condition for whether the solutions to a quadratic equation\
      \ will be\r\nrational.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 59
- fields:
    answer: "A polynomial is a multinomial in which each term contains $x$ raises\
      \ to a\r\nwhole-number power.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a polynomial\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 60
- fields:
    answer: "The degree is the highest power of $x$. A quadratic is a second-degree\r\
      \npolynomial.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the degree of a polynomial. Define a quadratic polynomial\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 61
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = -1/3, -3$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.25'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve \r\n$$y^2 + (3 1/3)y + 1 = 0$$\r\nby factoring.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 62
- fields:
    answer: "1. Yes\r\n2. No\r\n3. No.\r\n4. Yes\r\n5. It can be transformed into\
      \ a polynomial.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 11.30-34
    points: 2
    question: "Which of these algebraic expressions are polynomials:\r\n1. $2^2 -\
      \ 6x - 4$\r\n2. $x^3 + x^2 + x + 1 + x^{-1} + x^{-2} + x^{-3}$\r\n3. $(x^2 +\
      \ 3x + 4)/(x-5)$\r\n4. $(1/2)gt^2 + 40$\r\n5. $(1/y)(y^3 + 3y^2 + 3y + y)$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 63
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 3, -6$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.43'
    points: 3
    question: "Solve \r\n$$x^2 + 3x - 18 = 0$$\r\nby using the quadratic equation.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 64
- fields:
    answer: "x = -2\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.57'
    points: 1
    question: "Solve for $x$:\r\n$$2/x + 4/x^2 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 65
- fields:
    answer: "$x = 3, 2$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.59'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve for $x$:\r\n$$\\sqrt{5x - 6} = x$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 66
- fields:
    answer: "$$x^2 - 4x - 1 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '11.68'
    points: 2
    question: "Create a quadratic equation with solutions $x = 2 + \\sqrt{5}$ or\r\
      \n$x = 2 - \\sqrt{5}$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 67
- fields:
    answer: "Consider a general quadratic and complete the square:\r\n$$ax^2 + bx\
      \ + c = 0$$\r\n$$x^2 + bx/a + c/a = 0$$\r\n$$x^2 + bx/a + c/a -c/a + \\frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2\
      \ = -c/a + \\frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2$$\r\n$$(x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a))^2 = -c/a + \\\
      frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2$$\r\n$$(x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a))^2 = -ca/a^2 + \\frac{1}{4}(b/a)^2$$\r\
      \n$$(x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a))^2 = (-4ca + b)/(4a^2)$$\r\n$$x + \\frac{1}{2}(b/a)\
      \ = \\pm sqrt{-4ca + b}/(2a)$$\r\n$$x = \\frac{-b \\pm sqrt{b-4ac}}{2a}$$\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 5
    question: "Prove the quadratic formula\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 68
- fields:
    answer: "$$(x +\\frac{1}{2}b)^2 = x^2 + bx + \\frac{1}{4}b^2$$\r\nSo add $\\frac{1}{4}b^2\
      \ - c$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Given $x^2 + bx +c = 0$, what do you need to add to complete the square?\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 69
- fields:
    answer: "Factor out $a$ and complete the square. Then write\r\n$$(x- h)^2 + k$$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how to deal with non-monic quadratics w.r.t. completing the\
      \ square.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 70
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = \\frac{-b \\pm \\sqrt{ b^2 - 4ac } }{2a}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '11'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the quadratic equation:\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 49
  model: core.question
  pk: 71
- fields:
    answer: "A circle is the set of points (in a plane) such that every point on the\
      \ circle\r\nis the same distance (called the radius) from a fixed point (called\
      \ the\r\ncenter).\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a circle\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 72
- fields:
    answer: "An ellipse is the set of all points (in a plane) such that the sum of\
      \ the\r\ndistances to two fixed points is a constant. The two fixed points are\
      \ called\r\nthe foci.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Define an ellipse\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 73
- fields:
    answer: "It is the distance between focal points divided by the length of the\
      \ major\r\naxis.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the eccentricity of an ellipse\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 74
- fields:
    answer: "A parabola is a set of all points such that the distance to a fixed point\r\
      \n(called the focus) is the same as the distance to a fixed line (called the\r\
      \ndirectrix).\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a parabola\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 75
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.17'
    points: 2
    question: "Sketch the circle\r\n$$(x-5)^2 + (y-1)^2 = 16$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 76
- fields:
    answer: "$$h = -2$$\r\n$$k = -1$$\r\n$$r = \\sqrt{3}$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.17'
    points: 2
    question: "Identify the center and radius of the circle:\r\n$$x^2 + 4x + y^2 +\
      \ 2y + 2 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 77
- fields:
    answer: "$$e = 0.312$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.36'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate the eccentricity of the ellipse:\r\n$$x^2/10000 + y^2/(95^2)\
      \ = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 78
- fields:
    answer: "$$(3, -6)$$\r\n$$y = 4$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '12.50'
    points: 2
    question: "Identify the focus point and the equation of the directrix for\r\n\
      the parabola:\r\n$$y - 5 = (1/4)(x + 3)^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 79
- fields:
    answer: "$$x^2/a^2 + y^2/b^2 = 1$$\r\n$$y^2/b^2 = 1 - x^2/a^2$$\r\n$$y^2  = b^2(1\
      \ - x^2/a^2)$$\r\n$$y = \\pm b\\sqrt{1 - x^2/a^2}$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: '12.32'
    points: 3
    question: "Show that if $x$ is the $x$-coordinate of a point on an ellipse,\r\n\
      then $y$ can be found from the formula $y = \\pm b \\sqrt{1- x^2/a}$. (The center\r\
      \nis at the origin, the semimajor axis has length $a$ while the semiminor has\r\
      \nlength $b$)\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 80
- fields:
    answer: "If a point is a distance $r$ from $(a, b)$ then\r\n$$r = \\sqrt{ (x-a)^2\
      \ + (y-b)^2 }$$\r\n$$r^2 = (x-a)^2 + (y-b)^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Verify the equation of a circle of radius $r$ centered at $(a, b)$.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 81
- fields:
    answer: "The distance of a point $(x, y)$ to the focus $= \\sqrt{ (y - a)^2 +(x-0)^2\
      \ }$.\r\n\r\nThe distance of a point $(x, y)$ to the directrix $=y+a$\r\n\r\n\
      Thus:\r\n\r\n$$y+a = \\sqrt{ (y-a)^2 + x^2 }$$\r\n$$(y+a)^2 = |(y-a)^2 + x^2|\
      \ = (y-a)^2 + x^2$$\r\n$$y^2 + 2ay + a^2 = y^2 -2ay + a^2 + x^2$$\r\n$$4ay \
      \ = x^2$$\r\n$$y  = \\frac{1}{4a}x^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Find the equation for a parabola with focus at $(0, a)$ and directrix\
      \ at line\r\n$y = -a$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 82
- fields:
    answer: "$$(x - a)^2 + (y - b)^2 = r^2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give the equation of a circle with center $(a, b)$ and radius $r$.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 83
- fields:
    answer: "$$e = \\sqrt{ \\frac{a^2 - b^2}{a^2} }$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give a formula for the eccentricity of an ellipse:\r\n$$x^2/a^2 + y^2/b^2\
      \ = 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 84
- fields:
    answer: "$$(y - k) = \\frac{1}{4a}(x-h)^2\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '12'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give the formula for a parabola with vertex $(h, k)$ and focus $(h,\
      \ k + a)$:\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 50
  model: core.question
  pk: 85
- fields:
    answer: "If the degree of the polynomial is odd, then it has an even number of\
      \ turning\r\npoints, so it must have one solution since at the tails it points\
      \ opposite\r\nways.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Using the turning point rules, characterize roots of polynomials.\r\
      \n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 86
- fields:
    answer: "1) x = 0, -1, 5/2\r\n2) x = \\pm 2, \\pm 3\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '13.3'
    points: 4
    question: "Solve these equations for the unknown:\r\n\r\n1) $2x^3 - 3x^2 - 5x\
      \ = 0$\r\n\r\n2) $x^4  -13x^2 + 36 = 0$\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 87
- fields:
    answer: "$x = 1, 5, 10$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '13.39'
    points: 4
    question: "Find the solutions to these equations using the rational roots\r\n\
      theorem and synthetic division:\r\n$$x^3-16x^2+65x-50 = 0$$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 88
- fields:
    answer: "A polynomial curve of degree $n$ has a maximum of $n-1$ turning points.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: '13.39'
    points: 1
    question: "Characterize the number of turning points of a polynomial in terms\
      \ of the\r\npolynomial degree\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 89
- fields:
    answer: "An even [odd] polynomial will have an odd [even] number of turning points.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What can you say about even and odd polynomials?\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 90
- fields:
    answer: "If f is a polynomial with integer coefficients, then each rational root\
      \ can be \r\nexpressed as a fraction in which the numerator is a factor of the\
      \ constant term,\r\nand denominaotr a factor of the leading coefficient.\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '13'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the rational root theorem\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 51
  model: core.question
  pk: 91
- fields:
    answer: "A series in which the ratio between two consecutive terms is constant.\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a geometric series\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 92
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\sum_{i = 10}^{30} 2i$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '14.3'
    points: 1
    question: "Write using summation notation the sum of all even numbers from\r\n\
      20 to 60.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 93
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> 4\r\n<li> 2/11\r\n<li> 254\r\n<li> 0 (If $r =\
      \ -1$ then the sum will be 0 if $n$ is even and $a$ if $n$ is odd)\r\n</ol>\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 14.14,17,23,25,28
    points: 6
    question: "Calculate the sums of these series:\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> $-10\
      \ -7 - 4 - 1 + 2 + 5 + 8 + 11$\r\n<li> $18/100 + 18/10000 + 18/1000000 + \\\
      ldots$\r\n<li> $2 + 4 + 8 + 16 + 32 + 64 + 128$\r\n<li> $1 - 1 + 1 - 1 + 1 -\
      \ 1$\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 97
- fields:
    answer: "If $n$ is even we can pair these as:\r\n$$1 + n$$\r\n$$2 + n-1$$\r\n\
      $$3 + (n-2)$$\r\netc., so that we have $n/2$ pairs, each summing to $n+1$.\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Explain the formula for $\\sum_{i=0}^n i$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 98
- fields:
    answer: "Take\r\n$$\\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} r^i$$\r\nmultiply by $(r-1)$ and we get:\r\
      \n$$r^n  - 1$$ \r\nso \r\n$$\\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} ar^i = a \\frac{r^n - 1}{r-1}$$\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Prove the formula for a geometric series\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 99
- fields:
    answer: "$$(n/2)(n+1)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is $\\sum_{i=0}^n i$?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 100
- fields:
    answer: "$$a \\frac{r^n - 1}{r - 1}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '14'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "What is the general formula for $$\\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} ar^i$$?\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 52
  model: core.question
  pk: 101
- fields:
    answer: "$$n! = n \\times (n-1) \\times (n-2) \\times \\ldots \\times 4 \\times\
      \ 3 \\times 2\r\n\\times 1$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the factorial of a number $n$.\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 102
- fields:
    answer: "Selecting $j$ objects with order from $n$.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a permutation of $n$ objects taken $j$ at a time\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 103
- fields:
    answer: "Selecting $j$ objects without order from $n$.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a combination of $n$ objects taken $j$ at a time\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 104
- fields:
    answer: "For n \\in N and any 0 \\le k \\le n, define {n \\choose k} to be the\
      \ number of\r\nk-element subsets of the set {1, 2, ..., n}.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define {n \\choose k}.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 105
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\frac{n!}{j!(n-j)!} + \\frac{n!}{(j+1)!(n-j-1)!}$$\r\n$$=\\frac{n!(j+1)}{(j+1)j!(n-j)!}\
      \ + \\frac{n!(n-j)}{(j+1)!(n-j)(n-j-1)!}$$\r\n$$=\\frac{n!(j+1)}{(j+1)!(n-j)!}\
      \ + \\frac{n!(n-j)}{(j+1)!(n-j)!}$$\r\n$$=\\frac{n![j+1+n-j]{(j+1)!(n-j)!}$$\r\
      \n$$ = {n+1 \\choose j + 1}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: '15.7'
    points: 3
    question: "Show that ${n \\choose j} + {n \\choose j+1} = {n+1 \\choose j+1}$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 106
- fields:
    answer: "1 4 6 4 1 \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.11'
    points: 2
    question: "If you flip a coin 4 times, there are $2^4$ possible outcomes.\r\n\
      How many of these outcomes have 0 heads? How many have 1 head? 2 heads? 3\r\n\
      heads? 4 heads?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 107
- fields:
    answer: "$$6.35 \\times 10^{11}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.14'
    points: 1
    question: "How many 13-card hands can you draw from a deck of 52 cards?\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 108
- fields:
    answer: "15504\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.15'
    points: 1
    question: " How many ways can you select a 5-member committee from a group\r\n\
      of 20 people?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 109
- fields:
    answer: "$$a^6 + 12a^5 + 60a^4 + 160a^3 + 240a^2 + 192a + 64$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '15.21'
    points: 2
    question: "Use the binomial formula to write expressions for $(a + 2)^6$.\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 110
- fields:
    answer: "<ul>\r\n<li>(1, 2, 3)\r\n<li>(2, 1, 3)\r\n<li>(3, 1, 2)\r\n<li>(1, 3,\
      \ 2)\r\n<li>(2, 3, 1)\r\n<li>(3, 2, 1)\r\n</ul>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: Example 2.1.1
    points: 1
    question: "List all the permutations of the set of integers {1, 2,\r\n3}.\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 111
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\frac{n!}{(n-j)!}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '2.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "How many permutations of $n$ objects taken $j$ at a time are there?\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 112
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\frac{n!}{j!(n-j)!}$$\r\n\r\nThis is also ${n \\choose j}$.\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "How many combinations of $j$ objects from a group of $n$ objects are\
      \ there?\r\nWhat is another name for this?\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 113
- fields:
    answer: "$$(a + b)^n = \\sum_{i = 0}^n {n \\choose i}a^ib^{n-i}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '15'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Binomial formula\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 53
  model: core.question
  pk: 114
- fields:
    answer: "Note that you can prove this for various cases of n:\r\n\r\n<ul>\r\n\
      <li>n = 1: a = a\r\n<li>n = 2: a + (a+d) = 2a + d\r\n<li>n = 3: a + (a+d) +\
      \ (a + 2d) = 3a + 3d\r\n</ul>\r\nNote that once you go to n = 4, you can recognize\
      \ a previous term:\r\n\r\n$$a + (a+d) + (a+2d) + (a+3d) = 3a + 3d + a+3d = 4a\
      \ + 6d$$\r\n\r\nThis motivates the idea of doing this sort of substitution generically."
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Explain the motivation behind induction in terms of arithmetic series\
      \ formula.\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 115
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> The formula is true for $n = 1$ since it is $1\
      \ = 1^2$\r\n<li> Assume $S_{2n-1} = n^2.\r\n<li> Then $S_{2(n+1) - 1} = n^2\
      \ + (2n+1) - 1 = (n+1)^2$\r\n</ol>"
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '16.5'
    points: 2
    question: "Prove this formula by mathematical induction:\r\n$$1 + 3 +5 + 7 + \\\
      cdots + (2n-1) = n^2$$\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 116
- fields:
    answer: "1 is odd and $1^2$ is odd. Assume $n$ is odd and $n^2$ is odd. The next\
      \ odd\r\nnumber after $n$ is $n+2$. $(n+2)^2 = n^2 +4n+4 = n^2 + 2(2n+2)$. Since\
      \ this is\r\nthe sum of an odd and an even number, it follows that $(n+2)^2$\
      \ is odd.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '16.7'
    points: 4
    question: " Prove that if $n$ is odd, then $n^2$ is odd.\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 117
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> Show that the fact holds for $n = 1$.\r\n<li>\
      \ Next, assume the formula is true for an arbitrary number $j$.\r\n<li> Show\
      \ that *if* the formula is true for the number $j$, then it must also be\r\n\
      true for the number $j+1$.\r\n<li> Once you have completed these steps, then\
      \ the formula has been proved to be\r\ntrue for all whole numbers.\r\n</ol>\r\
      \n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '16'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "State the method of induction\r\n\r\n"
    section: 54
  model: core.question
  pk: 118
- fields:
    answer: "Think of generational growth\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give an example of how exponential growth occurs naturally.\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 119
- fields:
    answer: "For negative values $a^{-t} = 1/a^t$.\r\n\r\nwe define $a^{1/q} = \\\
      sqrt[q]{a}$.\r\n\r\nFor rational values:\r\n$$a^{p/q} = a^pa^{1/q}$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 3
    question: "Justify an exponential function for negative integers and rational\
      \ values\r\nassuming the definition for positive integers. Note that in this\
      \ level we do not\r\njustify irrational values.\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 120
- fields:
    answer: "$$F(x) = a^x$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an exponential function.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 121
- fields:
    answer: "$$10^{log x} = x$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the common logarithm\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 122
- fields:
    answer: "$$3\\log(x + 4) + \\log(a+b) -2\\log(x-1) - \\log(a^2 + b^2)$$\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '17.36'
    points: 2
    question: "Simplify\r\n$$\\log[ \\frac{(x+4)^3(a+b)}{(x-1)^2(a^2+b^2)}]$$\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 123
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\log(xy)  = \\log(x) + \\log(y)$$\r\n$$\\log(x/y) = \\log(x) - \\\
      log(y)$$\r\n$$\\log(x^n) = n\\log(x)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '17'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "State the rules of logarithms\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 55
  model: core.question
  pk: 124
- fields:
    answer: "It means that the planes do not have a common intersection. Either two\
      \ planes\r\nare parallel, or the three intersections of the planes are in three\
      \ parallel\r\nlines.\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.1'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 0
    question: "What does it mean geometrically if three equations in three unknowns\
      \ have no solution?\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 125
- fields:
    answer: "It is an equation of the form \r\n$$a_1x_1 + x_2x_2 + \\cdots x_nx_n\
      \ = b$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a linear equation in $n$ variables.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 126
- fields:
    answer: "A system of equations that has [at least one[no] solution is said to\
      \ be\r\n[in]consistent.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define an [in]consistent system of equations.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 127
- fields:
    answer: "$$a = 0.7906, b = 80.8837, c = 18.3255$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '18.7'
    points: 3
    question: "Solve this equation systems:\r\n\r\n$$a + b + c = 100$$\r\n$$b = 6\
      \ + 2a + 4c$$\r\n$$c = 12 + 8a$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 128
- fields:
    answer: "$$2x^2 - x - 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '18.13'
    points: 3
    question: "Find a second-degree polynomial that passes through each of\r\nthese\
      \ three points: $(6, 65), (7, 90), (10, 189)$.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 129
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> You can multiply both sides of one of the equations\
      \ by a number.\r\n<li> You can add one equation to another equation.\r\n<li>\
      \ You can add to one equation a multiple of another equation.\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '18'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "List legal moves to transform a system of equations\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 56
  model: core.question
  pk: 130
- fields:
    answer: "Ax = b is defined so that it represents a system of 3 equations in 3\
      \ unknowns\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Motivate the definition of Ax where A is a 3x3 matrix and x is a 3x1\
      \ vector.\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 131
- fields:
    answer: "Multiply both sides by $A^{-1}$:\r\n\r\n$$A^{-1}Ax = A^{-1}d$$\r\n$$Ix\
      \ = A^{-1}d$$\r\n$$x = A^{-1}d$$\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how to use $A^{-1}$ to solve $Ax = d$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 132
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> $\\det(A^{-1}) = \\frac{1}{det(A)}$\r\n<li> $\\\
      det(AB)     = \\det(AB)$\r\n<li> If $\\det(A) = 0$ then the matrix $A$ has no\
      \ inverse\r\n</ol>"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "State 3 properties of determinants:\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 133
- fields:
    answer: "A matrix is a rectangular array of numbers. Two matrices are equal if\
      \ they have the same size and their corresponding entries are equal.\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define a matrix and when two matrices are equal.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 134
- fields:
    answer: "The coefficients of the $a_ix_i$ terms along with the last column of\
      \ constant\r\nterms in a rectangular array.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the augmented matrix for a system of linear equations\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 135
- fields:
    answer: "The zero matrix an array of all zeros. For addition first note that the\
      \ matrices need to have the same dimensions. Then you just add component wise\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.1'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the zero matrix. Define addition of matrices\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 136
- fields:
    answer: "Multiply each element of the array by that scalar.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the multiplication of a matrix by a scalar.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 137
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li> start with the first row of A and the first column\
      \ of B.\r\n<li> multiply the corresponding elements of this row and column\r\
      \n<li> Add all the products together, and the result is the entry in the first\
      \ row\r\nand column of AB.\r\n<li> Repeat this process to find each element\
      \ of AB, using the ith row of A and\r\nthe jth columbn of B to get the element\
      \ in the ith row and jth column of AB.\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Define matrix multiplication: $AB$ (where the number of columns of\
      \ A equals the\r\nnumber of rows of B).\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 138
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\det \\begin{pmatrix} a_1 b_1 c_1 \\\\ a_2 b_2 c_2 \\\\ a_3 b_3 c_3\
      \ \\\\\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$ = a_1b_2c_3 + a_2b_3c_1 + a_3b_1c_2 - a_3b_2c_1\
      \ - a_2b_1c_3 - a_1b_3c_2$$"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the determinant of a 3x3 matrix\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 139
- fields:
    answer: "No: \r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 6 & 12 \\\\ 4 & 2 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\
      \n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} 11 & 6 \\\\ 1 & 7 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\nThen\
      \ \r\n$$AB = \\begin{pmatrix} 78 & 120 \\\\ 46 & 38 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\
      $$BA = \\begin{pmatrix} 90 & 144 \\\\ 34 & 26 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: E
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Is matrix multiplication commutative? If so prove it, if not give a\r\
      \ncounterexample.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 140
- fields:
    answer: "$$A + B = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    -2 & 4 & 5 & 4 \\\\ 1 & 2 & 2 & 3 \\\
      \\ 7 & 0 & 3 & 5 \r\n          \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$A - B = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\
      \n    6 & -2 & -5 & 2 \\\\ -3 & -2 & 2 & 5 \\\\ 1 & -4 & 11 & -5 \r\n      \
      \    \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$2A    = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    4 & 2 & 0 & 6 \\\\\
      \ -2 & 0 & 4 & 8 \\\\ 8 & -4 & 14 & 0 \r\n          \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$-\\\
      frac{1}{2}B = \\begin{pmatrix}\r\n    2 & -3/2 & -5/2 & -1/2 \\\\ -1 & -1 &\
      \ 0 & 1/2 \\\\ -3/2 & -1 & 2 & -5/2 \r\n          \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.3'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: Eg 1.3.3-4
    points: 3
    question: "For the matrices\r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 2 & 1 & 0 & 3 \\\\ -1 &\
      \ 0 & 2 & 4 \\\\ 4 & -2 & 7 & 0 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} -4\
      \ & 3 & 5 & 1 \\\\ 2 & 2 & 0 & -1 \\\\ 3 & 2 & -4 & 5\r\n\\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\
      Compute: $A + B$, $A - B$, $2A$, $(-\\frac{1}{2}B$:\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 141
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\begin{pmatrix} 132 & 92 \\\\ 92 & 62 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix} $$\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '19'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '19.3'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate\r\n$$\\begin{pmatrix} 4 & 12 \\\\ 4 & 7 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}\
      \ \\cdot\r\n  \\begin{pmatrix} 9 & 5 \\\\ 8 & 6 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 142
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = 6, y = 10, z = 4$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '19.21'
    points: 2
    question: "Downing 19.21: Use the matrix triangularization process to solve:\r\
      \n$$6x + 3y + 8z = 98$$\r\n$$5x + 11y - 9z = 104$$\r\n$$7x - 12y - 9z  -1144$\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 143
- fields:
    answer: "$$0$$\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '19.33'
    points: 1
    question: "Calculate the determinant of \r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 6 & 11 \\\\\
      \ 12 & 22 \\\\ \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 144
- fields:
    answer: "No:\r\n\r\n$$A = \\begin{pmatrix} 0 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 2 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\
      \n$$B = \\begin{pmatrix} 1 & 1 \\\\ 3 & 4 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n$$C = \\begin{pmatrix}\
      \ 2 & 5 \\\\ 3 & 4 \\end{pmatrix}$$\r\n\r\nThen $AB = AC$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: E
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.3
    points: 2
    question: "Does the cancellation law hold for Matrices? If so prove\r\nit, if\
      \ not give a counterexample.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 145
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\det \\begin{pmatrix} a & b \\\\ c & d \\\\ \\end{pmatrix} = ad -\
      \ bc$$\r\n$$\\det \\begin{pmatrix} b & a \\\\ d & c \\\\ \\end{pmatrix} = bc\
      \ - ad$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: '19.45'
    points: 3
    question: "Prove that for 2x2 matrices if you interchange two columns of\r\nthe\
      \ determinant, then the value of determinant changes sign.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 146
- fields:
    answer: "If $I$ is an identity matrix and $A$ is any other matrix with the same\
      \ number\r\nof rows as $I$, then $IA = A.$ Alsi if $B$ has the same number of\
      \ columns as\r\n$I$ then $BI = B$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State the Identity Matrix Property\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 147
- fields:
    answer: "Let $A_i$ represent replacing the $ith$ column of $A$ with the column\
      \ vector\r\n$d$.\r\n$$x = \\frac{ \\det(A_1) }{ \\det(A) }$$\r\n$$y = \\frac{\
      \ \\det(A_2) }{ \\det(A) }$$\r\n$$z = \\frac{ \\det(A_3) }{ \\det(A) }$$\r\n\
      \r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "State how to solve a 3x3 system using determinants:\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 148
- fields:
    answer: "<ol type=\"1\">\r\n<li>  $A + B = B + A$\r\n<li>  $A + (B + C) = (A+B)\
      \ + C$\r\n<li>  $A(BC) = (AB)C$\r\n<li>  $A(B + C) = AB + AC$\r\n<li>  $(B+C)A\
      \ = BA + CA$\r\n<li>  $A(B-C) = AB - AC$\r\n<li>  $(B-C)A = BA - CA$\r\n<li>\
      \  $a(B+C) = aB + aC$\r\n<li>  $a(B-C) = aB - aC$\r\n<li> $(a+b)C = aC + bC$\r\
      \n<li> $(a-b)C = aC - bC$\r\n<li> $a(bC)  = (ab)C$\r\n<li> $a(BC)  = (aB)C =\
      \ B(aC)$\r\n<li> $A + 0 = 0 + A = A$\r\n<li> $A - A = 0$\r\n<li> $A0 = 0$ and\
      \ $0A = 0$ (not $A0 = 0 = 0A$).\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '1.4'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 1.4.1
    points: 4
    question: "State the basic properties of arthmetic of Matrices over\r\nthe reals.\
      \ (hint there are 16)\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 57
  model: core.question
  pk: 149
- fields:
    answer: "A^{-1} = 1/det(A) [ d -b]\r\n                  [-c  a]\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '19'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Give the formula for the inverse of a 2x2 matrix in terms of determinants.\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 59
  model: core.question
  pk: 150
- fields:
    answer: "Considering quadratics where $b^2 - 4ac < 0$ such as $x^2 + x + 1 = 0$\r\
      \nnaturally leads to solutions where $\\sqrt{-1}$ needs to be considered."
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Give an example that leads us to imaginary numbers\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 151
- fields:
    answer: "Considering a complex number $a + bi$ (where $a$ and $b$ are real), we\
      \ can plot\r\nthis number on the x-y plane by the coordinates $(a, b)$."
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the idea behind the complex plane.\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 152
- fields:
    answer: "By using the idea that $a + bi$ is a point on the complex plane, we note\
      \ that\r\nthe length of the vector from the origin to this point is $\\sqrt{a^2\
      \ + b^2}$.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: C
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Motivate the definition of the absolute value of a complex number\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 153
- fields:
    answer: "An imaginary number is a multiple of $i = \\sqrt{-1}$. Thus $ai = \\\
      sqrt{-a^2}$. A complex number is A real number plus an imaginary number. The\
      \ real number is called the real part\r\nand the imaginary number is called\
      \ the imaginary part.\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define imaginary and complex numbers.\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 154
- fields:
    answer: "a + bi = c + di if a = c and b = d\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define when two complex numbers are equal.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 155
- fields:
    answer: "$$|a + bi| = \\sqrt{a^2 + b^2}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: D
    concepts: []
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the absolute value (or modulus) of a complex number\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 156
- fields:
    answer: "$$41 + 129i$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.14'
    points: 2
    question: "Calculate \r\n$$(4 + 11i)(6-2i) + (3 + 5i)(10 + 7i)$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 157
- fields:
    answer: "$$x = -4 \\pm 3i$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.14'
    points: 2
    question: "Find the solution to \r\n$$x^2 + 8x + 25 = 0$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 158
- fields:
    answer: "$$6/5 + (9/10)i$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.59'
    points: 1
    question: "Simplify \r\n$$\\frac{ 3 + 6i }{ 4 + 2i }$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\
      \r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 159
- fields:
    answer: "$$i - 1$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 2
    book_section: '20'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: '20.64'
    points: 2
    question: "Solve for $z$\r\n\r\n$$(i+1)z = -2$$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 160
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.1'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 10.1.1
    points: 1
    question: "Plot the point given below:\r\n<ol type=\"a\">\r\n<li> 2 + 3i\r\n<li>\
      \ -4\r\n<li> -3-2i\r\n<li> -5i\r\n</ol>\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 161
- fields:
    answer: "\r\n\r\n\r\n|z| = 5\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: X
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.2
    points: 1
    question: "Find |z| if z = 3 - 4i\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 162
- fields:
    answer: "if z = a+bi then\r\n\r\nzz^* = (a+bi)(a-bi)\r\n     = a^2 -b^2i^2\r\n\
      \     = a^2 + b^2\r\n     = |z|^2\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.1
    points: 1
    question: "Prove that $zz^* = |z|^2$ for any complex number $z$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 163
- fields:
    answer: "$z = 1/|z_2|^2 \\cdot z_1z_2^*$\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: P
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.2
    points: 1
    question: "If $z_2 \\ne 0$, then what is the solution of $z_1 = z_2z$, given $z_1$\
      \ and $z_2$.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 164
- fields:
    answer: "1) (z_1 + z_2)^* = z_1^* + z_2^*\r\n2) (z_1 - z_2)^* = z_1^* - z_2^*\r\
      \n3) (z_1z_2)^* = z_1^*z_2^*\r\n4) (z_1/z_2)^* = z_1^*/z_2^*\r\n5) z^*^* = z\r\
      \n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '10.2'
    category: S
    concepts: []
    index: 10.2.3
    points: 3
    question: "For any complex numbers $z$, $z_1$ and $z_2$, state 5\r\nproperties\
      \ of the complex conjugate.\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    section: 58
  model: core.question
  pk: 165
- fields:
    answer: "Vectors can be represented geometrically as directed line segments or\
      \ arrows in\r\n2- or 3-space. The tail of the arrow is called the initial point\
      \ and then tip\r\nof the arrow is called the terminal point."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: C
    concepts: [1]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain how a vector is represented and use the terms initial point\
      \ and terminal\r\npoint."
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 166
- fields:
    answer: "$v + w$: Position the vector $w$ so that its initial point concides with\
      \ the\r\nterminal point of $v$. The vector $v+w$ has initial point the same\
      \ as $v$ and\r\nterminal point of $w$ as so positioned. Then we define the negative\
      \ - $-v$: The vector whose terminal point is the initial point of $v$ and whose\r\
      \ninitial point is the terminal point of $v$. Finally using these two definitions,\
      \ the difference: $v - w = v + (-w)$.\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: D
    concepts: [1]
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: Define the sum and difference of two vectors geometrically.
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 167
- fields:
    answer: "$$|u| = \\sqrt{v_1^2 + v_2^2 + v_3^2}$$\r\n\r\n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: D
    concepts: [6]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the length (or norm) of a vector $v = (v_1, v_2, v_3)$ in 3-space.\r\
      \n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 168
- fields:
    answer: "$$\\sqrt{ (u_1 - v_1)^2 + (u_2 - v_2)^2 + (u_3 - v_3)^2 }$$\r\n\r\n\r\
      \n\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: D
    concepts: [8]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the distance between two vectors $(u_1, u_2, u_3)$ and $(v_1,\
      \ v_2, v_3)$\r\nin 3-space.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 169
- fields:
    answer: "$$u \\cdot v = |u||v| \\cos \\theta.$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: D
    concepts: [1, 6]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Define the dot product of two 2- or 3-vectors where $\\theta$ is the\
      \ angle\r\nbetween u and v."
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 170
- fields:
    answer: "$$v = (7 - 2, 5 - (-1), (-8) - 4) = (5, 6, -12)$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: P
    concepts: [3]
    index: Example 3.1.2
    points: 1
    question: "Give the components of the vector $v = \\arrow{P_1P_2}$\r\nwith initial\
      \ point $(2, -1, 4)$ and terminal point $(7, 5, -8)$.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 171
- fields:
    answer: "$$(2, -1, 1) \\cdot (1, 1, 2) = 2 - 1 + 2 = 3$$\r\n$$= |(2, -1, 1)||(1,\
      \ 1, 2)| \\cos \\theta$$\r\nSo,\r\n$$\\frac{ 3 }{ \\sqrt{6}\\sqrt{6} } = \\\
      cos \\theta$$\r\n$$\\theta = \\pi/3$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: X
    concepts: [1, 8]
    index: Eg 3.2.2
    points: 2
    question: "Consider the vectors (2, -1, 1) and $(1, 1, 2)$ and find\r\nthe angle\
      \ between them."
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 172
- fields:
    answer: "The set of points $p$ is the set of points on the sphere of radius 1\
      \ whose\r\ncenter is at the point $p_0$."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.2'
    category: X
    concepts: [7]
    index: 3.2.8
    points: 1
    question: "Let $p_0 = (x_0, y_0, z_0)$ and $p = (x, y, z)$. Describe the set\r\
      \nof all points $p$ for which $|p - p_0| = 1$."
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 173
- fields:
    answer: "$$p = tq$$\r\n$$(2, k) = (3t, 5t)$$\r\n$$t = 2/3$$\r\n$$p = (2, 10/3)$$"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: X
    concepts: [1, 9]
    index: 3.3.14
    points: 2
    question: "Let $p = (2, k)$ and $q = (3, 5)$ Find $k$ such that \r\n$p$ and $q$\
      \ are parallel.\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 174
- fields:
    answer: "$$(a, b, c) \\cdot (x, y, z) = (ax, by, cz)$$\r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.3'
    category: S
    concepts: [1, 7]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "State, without proof, the simplified formula for the dot product (that\
      \ is the\r\nformula in terms of components, not in terms of angles.)\r\n\r\n"
    section: 2
  model: core.question
  pk: 175
- fields:
    answer: "Select a point O, called the origin. and choose three mutually perpendicular\r\
      \nlines, called coordinate axes, passing through the origin. Label these axis\r\
      \n$x$, $y$, and $z$. and select a positive direction for each coordinate axis."
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: C
    concepts: [3]
    index: ''
    points: 2
    question: "Explain how to construct a rectangular coordinate system to describe\
      \ vectors in\r\n3-space.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 176
- fields:
    answer: "A right-handed system has the property that an ordinary screw pointed\
      \ in the\r\npositive direction on the z-axis would be advanced if the positive\
      \ $x$-axis is\r\nrotated 90 degrees toward the positive $y$-axis. \r\n"
    book: 1
    book_section: '3.1'
    category: C
    concepts: [3]
    index: ''
    points: 1
    question: "Explain the difference between a left-handed versus right-handed coordinate\r\
      \nsystem.\r\n"
    section: 1
  model: core.question
  pk: 177
- fields: